

Yudan Zhai

Front End Developer, MSc in Computer Science

Info

Address

Lehnstrasse 42, St.Gallen, 9014, Switzerland

Phone

+41 78 807 73 58

Email

zhai.yudan@gmail.com

Nationality

China (with permit C)

Links

yudan.ch - about me

Linkedin - about my career

Skills

ES6

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

HTML & CSS

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

SASS

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Node.js

• • • • •

jQuery

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Bootstrap

 \bullet

РНР

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

MySQL

 \bullet

Apache

 \bullet \bullet \bullet

Profile

With 6 years of academic background and more than 5 years of work experience in the Web industry, I have sound and up-to-date knowledge in Web Design technologies. My experience on the back end helps me to understand the potential and boundary of the technical stack, thus being able to turn the implicit requirement into explicit and realistic implementation.

As a foreigner holding a settlement permit (C), I am allowed to work without restriction.

Employment History

Full-Stack Engineer, Project Manager, University of Fribourg

Dec 2006 − Oct 2007 Fribourg

I was responsible for a wiki based website using data recommendation algorithm.

- Led the entire development cycle of the website
- Using AJAX in the development of the UI
- · Designed the database structure
- Installed and maintained the web-servers
- Trained new team members and internships

Senior Software Engineer, Sina.com

I was developing and maintaining a productive Content Management System for mobile devices

- Implemented mobile device-oriented UI for the CMS from concept through development
- User Interface adaptation for all screen sizes ranging from PC to WAP mobile phones
- Web server administration

Software Engineer & Database Developer, Sina.com

Aug 2004 − Jun 2005 Peijing

I was working in the supporting section of the R&D department.

- Being responsible for the R&D of the Finance channel of the online portal.
- Full implementation of the online trading module of financial products.
- Agile development using PHP and MySQL.

Education

Languages

English

 \bullet \bullet \bullet

German

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Mandarin Chinese

ullet

ETH Zürich, Master of Science in Management, Technology and Economics

The master program was a continuation for students with a solid background on science and engineering. The program focused on the management and application of technologies.

Université de Fribourg, Master of Science in Computer Science

The program focused on the advanced knowledge of modern computing. Besides a series of fundamental courses in algorithms, programming languages and mathematics, there were also several real-life projects involving web-design, logical thinking and commercial development.

Beijing University of Technology, Bachelor in computer science

Courses

Build Responsive Real World Websites with HTML5 and CSS3, Udemy Aug $2019 - Jul\ 2020$

The Complete JavaScript Course, Udemy

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020

JavaScript: the Advanced Concepts, Udemy

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020

The Complete Web Developer in 2020, Udemy

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020

German language course, HDS

Aug 2014 - Jul 2016

References

References available upon request